[
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the International Event Ambassador for the 20th Mumbai Marathon?",
        "options": [
            "Usain Bolt",
            "Eliud Kipchoge",
            "Mo Farah",
            "Haile Gebrselassie"
        ],
        "answer": "Mo Farah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has Levi\u2019s roped in as its new global brand ambassador?",
        "options": [
            "Ranbir Kapoor",
            "Deepika Padukone",
            "Diljit Dosanjh",
            "Shah Rukh Khan"
        ],
        "answer": "Diljit Dosanjh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who assumed office as the Controller General of Defence Accounts (CGDA) on March 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Giridhar Aramane",
            "Ajay Kumar",
            "Dr. Mayank Sharma",
            "T. V. Somanathan"
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. Mayank Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the current Chairman of the Bar Council of India (BCI) as mentioned in the recent appointments?",
        "options": [
            "R. Venkataramani",
            "Manan Kumar Mishra",
            "Harish Salve",
            "Amit Sibal"
        ],
        "answer": "Manan Kumar Mishra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the new Prime Minister of Tonga, securing 16 votes in parliament, following the resignation of Siaosi Sovaleni?",
        "options": [
            "Viliami Latu",
            "Siaosi Sovaleni",
            "Aisake Valu Eke",
            "Akilisi Pohiva",
            "Rahsail Bino"
        ],
        "answer": "Aisake Valu Eke"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was recently appointed as the Secretary of the Department of Revenue, Ministry of Finance in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Rajiv Kumar",
            "Ajay Bhushan Pandey",
            "Subhash Chandra Garg",
            "Arunish Chawla",
            "Nagendra Rajawat"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as India's doubles badminton coach, marking his return to the country in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Vimal Kumar",
            "Gopichand Pullela",
            "Morten Frost",
            "Tan Kim Her",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has taken over as the President of the Asian Cricket Council (ACC)?",
        "options": [
            "Jay Shah",
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Imran Khwaja",
            "Shammi Silva",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new CEO of DBS Bank India, effective March 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Surojit Shome",
            "Rajat Verma",
            "Piyush Gupta",
            "Gautam Jain",
            "Vedant Mahajan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new Chairperson of the National Human Rights Commission (NHRC) in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Justice Arun Kumar Mishra",
            "Justice H.L. Dattu",
            "Justice K.G. Balakrishnan",
            "Justice V. Ramasubramanian",
            "Justice D.Y. Chandrachud"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new Managing Director (MD) and Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of J&K Bank, effective December 30, 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Baldev Prakash",
            "Amitava Chatterjee",
            "Dinesh Khara",
            "Rajnish Kumar",
            "Shamsheer Mattoo"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new Chairperson of NABL, succeeding Prof. Subbanna Ayyappan?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Sandip Shah",
            "Dr. Subbanna Ayyappan",
            "Prof. Rajesh Kumar",
            "Dr. Ramesh Patel",
            "Prof. Brijesh Khaitan"
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. Sandip Shah"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of the Unique Identification Authority of India (UIDAI) with effect from January 2, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Amit Agrawal",
            "Bhuvnesh Kumar",
            "Ajay Bhushan Pandey",
            "R. S. Sharma",
            "Rajesh Kumar Singh"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the executive director of Dhanlaxmi Bank for a term of three years in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "P. Suriaraj",
            "Zulfiqar Hasan",
            "Amrit Mohan Prasad",
            "Priyanka Aggarwal",
            "Nandini Kulasekara"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General (D-G) of the Central Reserve Police Force (CRPF) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Anish Dayal Singh",
            "Vitul Kumar",
            "Gyanendra Pratap Singh",
            "Rakesh Asthana",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who recently assumed command of the Indian Air Force's Western Air Command? (January 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Air Marshal Pankaj Mohan Sinha",
            "Air Marshal Raghunath Nambiar",
            "Air Marshal Jeetendra Mishra",
            "Air Marshal Anil Chopra",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has recently been appointed as the Chief Vigilance Officer (CVO) of Bharat Electronics Limited (BEL)?",
        "options": [
            "Anil Kumar Gupta",
            "Suresh Chandra",
            "Ramesh Kumar Singh",
            "Nilabhra Sengupta",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Nilabhra Sengupta"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Financial Officer (CFO) of Oil India Limited (OIL)? (December 2024)",
        "options": [
            "Rupam Barua",
            "Ramesh Kumar",
            "Trailukya Borgohain",
            "Abhijit Majumder",
            "Tabish Seher"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new CEO of DBS Bank India effective March 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Surojit Shome",
            "Piyush Gupta",
            "Rajat Verma",
            "Anand Kumar",
            "Rajeev Ahuja"
        ],
        "answer": "Rajat Verma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been granted an extension of tenure as the Drug Controller General of India (DCGI)?",
        "options": [
            "Rajeev Singh Raghuvanshi",
            "S. Eswara Reddy",
            "Ramesh Kumar Gupta",
            "V. G. Somani",
            "Harsh Vardhan"
        ],
        "answer": "Rajeev Singh Raghuvanshi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who became the first Indian American FBI Director?",
        "options": [
            "Kamala Harris",
            "Kash Patel",
            "Bobby Jindal",
            "Sundar Pichai",
            "Arun Kumar"
        ],
        "answer": "Kash Patel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the \u2018Principal Secretary-2\u2019 to Prime Minister Narendra Modi after serving as RBI Governor?",
        "options": [
            "Raghuram Rajan",
            "Shaktikanta Das",
            "Urjit Patel",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman",
            "Arvind Subramanian"
        ],
        "answer": "Shaktikanta Das"
    },
    {
        "question": "Recently SCO Secretary General holds talks with MEA Secretary, Who is the current Secretary-General of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization (SCO)?",
        "options": [
            "Zhang Ming",
            "Nurlan Yermekbayev",
            "Sergey Lavrov",
            "Wang Yi",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Additional Director General, Directorate General of Foreign Trade (DGFT), as of February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Anant Swarup",
            "Samar Nanda",
            "Santosh Kumar Verma",
            "Abhinav Gupta",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new Chief Election Commissioner (CEC) of India in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Sukhbir Singh Sandhu",
            "Vivek Joshi",
            "Rajiv Kumar",
            "Gyanesh Kumar",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is set to take oath as the Chief Minister of Delhi after winning the Shalimar Bagh seat in the recent Assembly election?",
        "options": [
            "Rekha Gupta",
            "Vijender Gupta",
            "Harsh Vardhan",
            "Parvesh Verma",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Rekha Gupta"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Deputy Secretary in the Department of Expenditure under the Central Staffing Scheme?",
        "options": [
            "Sanjay Malhotra",
            "T.V. Somanathan",
            "Girish Chandra Murmu",
            "Mrithinjai Srikanthan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Mrithinjai Srikanthan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the new Prime Minister of Vanuatu in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Stephen Felix",
            "Charlot Salwai",
            "Jotham Napat",
            "Ishmael Kalsakau",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Executive Officer of Standard Chartered India, effective April 1, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Zarin Daruwala",
            "Deepak Parekh",
            "P D Singh",
            "Aditya Puri",
            "Mohak Singh"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the captain of Royal Challengers Bengaluru (RCB) for IPL 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Virat Kohli",
            "Faf du Plessis",
            "Rajat Patidar",
            "Glenn Maxwell",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been nominated as the U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for South Asian Affairs, replacing Donald Lu?",
        "options": [
            "Richard Verma",
            "Paul Kapur",
            "Nisha Biswal",
            "Vivek Murthy",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was confirmed as the U.S. intelligence chief in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Daniel Coats",
            "Robert Brook",
            "Tulsi Gabbard",
            "Avril Haines",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been given the additional charge as Secretary of the Ministry of New and Renewable Energy (MNRE)? (Jan 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Alok Ranjan",
            "Nidhi Khare",
            "Rajiv Singh",
            "Preeti Sharma",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed Director of the Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "S. Somanath",
            "R. Umamaheswaran",
            "P. Kunhikrishnan",
            "M. Mohan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General (DG) of the Directorate General of Civil Aviation (DGCA) as of January 3, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Vikram Dev Dutt",
            "Dinesh Chand Sharma",
            "Faiz Ahmed Kidwai",
            "Rajiv Bansal",
            "Arun Kumar"
        ],
        "answer": "Faiz Ahmed Kidwai"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as Ireland's Prime Minister (Taoiseach) for the second time in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Miche\u00e1l Martin",
            "Enda Kenny",
            "Leo Varadkar",
            "Mary Lou McDonald",
            "Laurie Brentford"
        ],
        "answer": "Miche\u00e1l Martin"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been sworn in as the 25th Governor of Mizoram? (Jan 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Anil Chauhan",
            "V K Singh",
            "Arvind Kumar",
            "Manoj Sinha",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as an independent observer for Chandigarh's mayoral election on January 30?",
        "options": [
            "Justice (retd) Jaishree Thakur",
            "Justice (retd) Kurian Joseph",
            "Justice (retd) Deepak Gupta",
            "Justice (retd) Madan Lokur",
            "None of the abocve"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice (retd) Jaishree Thakur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Ombudsman and Ethics Officer of the Board of Control for Cricket in India? (January 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Justice Arun Mishra",
            "Prabhtej Singh Bhatia",
            "Devajit Saikia",
            "Jay Shah"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice Arun Mishra"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Director General of the Bureau of Police Research and Development (BPR&D) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Barinder Jeet Singh",
            "Neeru Garg",
            "P Renuka Devi",
            "Senthil Avudai Krishna Raj S",
            "Brajesh Punia"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Secretary of the Department of Higher Education, Ministry of Education?",
        "options": [
            "Rajesh Kumar Sinha",
            "Vineet Joshi",
            "Alok Kumar Gupta",
            "Pankaj Choudhary",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been selected for the Ayyan Thiruvalluvar Award for 2025, announced by the Tamil Nadu government?",
        "options": [
            "M. Padikkaramu",
            "Viduthalai Rajendran",
            "L. Ganesan",
            "Kabilan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was elected as the President of Lebanon in January 2025, ending a two-year power vacuum?",
        "options": [
            "Michel Aoun",
            "Hassan Diab",
            "Joseph Aoun",
            "Najib Mikati",
            "Benjamin Frank"
        ],
        "answer": "Joseph Aoun"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been reappointed as the MD & CEO of IDBI Bank for another three-year term starting March 19, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Amitabh Chaudhry",
            "Sandeep Bakshi",
            "Sumant Kathpalia",
            "Rakesh Sharma",
            "Byomkesh Shastri"
        ],
        "answer": "Rakesh Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the chairperson of the Athletics Federation of India's (AFI) Athletes Commission?",
        "options": [
            "P. T. Usha",
            "Anju Bobby George",
            "Mary Kom",
            "Hima Das",
            "Deepa Karmakar"
        ],
        "answer": "Anju Bobby George"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the officiating Director General of the CRPF following the retirement of Anish Dayal Singh?",
        "options": [
            "Vitul Kumar",
            "R.K. Vishwakarma",
            "Alok Kumar",
            "Sunil Raj Awasthee",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was sworn in as a Supreme Court judge on January 16, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Justice R. Banumathi",
            "Justice S. Ravindra Bhat",
            "Justice K Vinod Chandran",
            "Justice Siddappa Sunil Dutt Yadav",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Justice K Vinod Chandran"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who among the following has been elected as a board member of the Marylebone Cricket Club (MCC) Advisory Board in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Kumar Sangakkara",
            "Jay Shah",
            "Sourav Ganguly",
            "Rahul Dravid",
            "Sanjay Bangar"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chairman and Managing Director (CMD) of the Food Corporation of India (FCI)? (January 2025)",
        "options": [
            "Rajiv Bansal",
            "Anil Kumar Jain",
            "Ashutosh Agnihotri",
            "Ajay Bhushan Pandey",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Ashutosh Agnihotri"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of NASSCOM Foundation with immediate effect from January 2, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Nidhi Bhasin",
            "Jyoti Sharma",
            "Debjani Ghosh",
            "Aruna Sundararajan",
            "Ritu Anand"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which actor has been appointed as the first Brand Ambassador for FICCI Frames?",
        "options": [
            "Kartik Aaryan",
            "Ayushman Khurana",
            "Vicky Kaushal",
            "Ranveer Singh",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Ayushman Khurana"
    }
]